停住  停住
Hold water. Hold water.
什么东西啊
What is that?
可怕的谋杀  惊悚  刺激
Gruesome murders, chills and thrills...
这就是作家卡塞尔闻名天下的东西
It's what author richard Castle is known for,
他又发布了两本新书
And he's delivered yet again with two new books...
《狂野斯道姆》和《狂怒希特》
"Wild Storm" and "Raging Heat."
谢谢你今早能来
Thank you for joining us this morning.
很荣幸
My pleasure.
但最大的谜团似乎是围绕着你的那个
But perhaps the bigger mystery is the one that surrounds you.
你的失踪登上了全国报纸头条
Your disappearance made national headlines.
几个月后  你在海上一艘小艇上被发现
Months later, you were found in a dinghy at sea,
而你却说完全不记得
Yet you claim to have no memory
自己去了哪里  怎么跑到小艇上
of where you've been or how you got there.
是啊  我知道这听上去很疯狂  我都这么觉得
Yeah, I know it, uh... it sounds crazy, even to me,
我们还在寻找答案
and, uh, we're still looking for answers.
你的评论家似乎有些看法
Well, your critics seem to have some.
这并不是秘密了  你上本书《狂野斯道姆》
It's no secret your last book, "Wild Storms,"
没能登上畅销榜
slipped off the best-seller list.
那么最合理的解释
Isn't the most logical explanation
难道不是这只是宣传手段吗
that this is all a publicity stunt,
让你登上头条  给新书促销
a way to make headlines to drum up book sales?
我保证  布鲁克  这绝非宣传手段
I assure you, Brooke, it was no publicity stunt.
我绝不会这么折磨我的家人和未婚妻
I would never do that to my family of my fiance.
说到你的未婚妻
Speaking of your fiance,
你正是在婚礼前失踪的
you vanished just moments before your wedding.
你要对认为你的失踪只是怯婚的粉丝说些什么
What do you say to fans who chalk your disappearance up to cold feet?
我要说  他们根本不了解情况
Well, I would say that they don't know what they're talking about.
那么婚礼还会举行吗
So the wedding's still on.
我们经历了一段折磨
Well, we've been through a very tough experience.
我们还在想办法解释一切
We're still trying to make sense o-of everything, actually.
其实...
And I actually just... I-I...
我是来谈我的书的
I came here to talk about my books.
如果这是您写的一本书  卡塞尔先生
And if this were one of your books, Mr. Castle,
你不会觉得这情节有点难以置信吗
wouldn't you find the plot a little hard to swallow?
失忆症  拜托啊
I mean, amnesia, really?
但这不是小说  布鲁克
Well, this isn't a novel, Brooke.
这是确有其事
This actually happened.
没有人比我更想知道真相
And no one wants the truth more than I do.
我可以证明
And I can prove it.
我要悬赏25万美金
I'm offering a reward... $250,000...
奖赏任何能拿出切实证据
to anyone who can give me verifiable proof
证明我失踪两个月内究竟身在何处
as to where I was and exactly what I was doing
做了什么的人
during the two months I was missing.
那就不是采访
That wasn't an interview.
简直是埋伏
That was an ambush.
你怎么想的啊  居然给出25万元的悬赏
And what were you thinking offering a quarter-million-dollar reward?
很聪明吧
Genius, right?
我真不知自己怎么没早点想到
I don't know why I didn't think of it sooner.
也行因为你知道
Well, maybe because you knew
这只会吸引疯子和投机者
it was gonna lure crackpots and opportunists,
我们不会跟进真正的线索
and instead of going after real leads,
而是追踪数几千个拿你的悬赏机会当彩票的
we're gonna be chasing thousands of half-baked tipsters
疯癫线人提供的情报
playing the Richard Castle lottery.
什么真正的线索
What real leads?
目前为止  我们一直在走死胡同
So far, we've had nothing but dead ends.
我受够蒙在鼓里的感觉了
And I'm tired of not knowing.
要想大海捞针
No, to find a needle in a haystack,
首先我们需要大海吧
do we not first need a haystack?
是啊  但不是满是疯子的大海
Yeah, but not a haystack full of nutjobs.
你也看见访谈了  没人信我
You saw that interview. No one believes me.
但是外面有人
But somewhere out there,
知道我去过哪里  做了什么
someone knows where I was and what I was doing.
你准备好了吗
You ready for this?
我或许能解决的谜团吗
A mystery I might be able to solve?
这会是解脱
It'll be a relief.
-卡塞尔  欢迎回来  -谢谢
- Hey, Castle. Welcome back. - Thank you.
听说东河今天比平常污染更严重一些
I hear the East River's a little more polluted than usual today.
是啊  一队船员
Yeah. A crew team,
在河里发现了塑料包裹着的尸体
they found the body in the river wrapped in plastic.
可能是有人扔进河里  想毁尸灭迹
Someone probably dumped it hoping to make it disappear.
他们没有绑足够沉的东西
They didn't weigh it down enough.
-死者是谁  -他身上没有身份证
- So, who's the victim? - Well, he didn't have an I.D. on him,
但我们将他和一个失踪人口匹配了
but we matched it to a missing-persons.
华莱士·威利格  45岁
Wallace Williger, 45,
威利格玩具公司的业主和总裁
Owner and C.E.O. of Williger Toys.
-制造阳光莎拉的吗  -阳光莎拉是什么
- Makers of Sunshine Sarah? - Sunshine Sarah?
她是个朝气蓬勃的红发布娃娃
She's a spunky, redheaded rag doll.
阿莱克西斯小时候最喜欢的娃娃
Alexis' favorite when she was growing up.
-去哪都会带着她  -他什么时候失踪的
- Wouldn't go anywhere without her. - When did he go missing?
上周五  也就是四天以前
Last Friday, so four days ago.
他妻子萨曼莎说
His wife, Samantha, said
他出去看电影了  然后就再也没有回来
he went off to the movies and never came back.
-这什么情况  -贝克特没有告诉你吗
- Something I should know? - Oh, Beckett didn't tell you?
你的失踪让他们重归于好了
Yeah, yeah, your disappearance kind of drove them back together.
人生苦短什么的
Life being short and all that.
才失踪两个月
Oh. Disappear for two months.
初步检查表明他的脖子断了
So, the prelim exam indicates his neck was broken.
鉴于他身上的防御性伤口  可能是因为搏斗
Probably after a struggle given his defensive wound.
幸运的是  尸体掉进水里时是用塑料包裹着的
Luckily, his body was wrapped when it went into the water.
我也许还可以从死者的手指甲里
I may still be able to pull the attacker's DNA
提取出凶手的DNA
From under the victim's nails.
等等  他死了多长时间了
Wait. How long has he been dead?
至少有几天了
At least a couple of days.
他的脸和手怎么了
What happened to his face and hands?
看起来像是被烧过
They look like they've been burned.
说真的  我不知道
Honestly, I don't know,
但尸体的其余部分没有遭到感染
but the rest of the body wasn't affected.
我带他回实验室后会了解更多情况
I'll know more when I get him back to the lab.
他没回家时  我感觉很不安心  但是...
I had that sick feeling when he didn't come home, but...
人总往好的方面想
you hope.
威利格太太  有谁
Mrs. Williger, was there anyone
会想伤害你的丈夫吗
that would've wanted to do your husband harm?
没有
No.
他靠制造玩具为生
He made toys for a living.
他是个好人
He was a decent man.
但是...
But...
但是什么
But what?
过去几周里  他很难熬
These last few weeks, he had been having a hard time.
自从安妮去世后
Ever since Annie died.
抱歉  安妮是谁
Oh, I'm sorry. Um...who's Annie?
我们的拉布拉多寻回犬
Our labrador retriever.
她去世后  沃利开始工作到很晚
And after she died, Wally started working late,
在我睡觉后才回家  像是在躲着我
coming home after I was asleep, like he was avoiding me.
你跟他谈过这事吗
Did you talk to him about it?
我试过  他说没事
I tried. He said everything was fine.
他只是在忙活一个重要项目
He was just working on an important project.
他消失的那天呢
And what about the day that he disappeared?
他说过什么暗示了自己有麻烦的话吗
Did he say anything that would indicate he was in trouble?
没有  他很幸福
No. He was happy.
他告诉我  他爱我
He told me he loved me,
说事情很快就会好起来
said things would be... better soon.
看到她以后  我简直难以想象你那么多夜晚
You know, seeing her, I can't imagine what it was like for you
毫不知情时心里的感受
all those nights, not knowing.
我很走运  你回来了
I was lucky. You came back.
我们查看了威利格的手机记录和财务情况
So, we took a look at Williger's phone and financials.
他失踪那天没有消费记录
There was no activity on the day he disappeared.
如果他真是去看电影了
If he was on his way to the movies,
要么他就没去成  要么就是用现金付的款
either he didn't make it there or he paid with cash.
查查当地的电影院  看有没有人见过他
Canvass local theaters, see if anyone saw him.
再查查他过去几周的记录
And take a look at his records for the past couple of weeks,
看看有没有什么异常
See if there's anything out of the ordinary there.
我和卡塞尔去他的办公室
Castle and I are gonna go to his office
-看看那边有没有什么问题  -马上去
- and check if there were any problems at work. - Right on.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
你到底以为你在干什么
Just what in the hell do you think you're doing?
你把局里的电话号码留给电视台了吗
Did you give that TV station the precinct number?
我总不能把自家电话给他们啊  那是隐私
I'm not gonna give them my home phone. That's private.
纽约警局可不是你的私人助理
The NYPD is not your personal secretary.
你知道你的这点小噱头
Did you know how many man-hours
耗费了我们多少人力物力吗
this little stunt of yours is costing us?
电话都快被打爆了
The phones have been ringing off the hook!
听到没
Did you hear that?!
打爆了
Ringing off the hook?
有线索了
We have leads.
什么情况
What just happened?
卡塞尔  你想什么呢
Castle, what were you thinking?
"不战而屈人之兵
"The supreme art of war
善之善者也"  孙子说的
is to subdue the enemy without fighting," Sun tzu.
那个战术之吻只是我浩瀚军械库里的一样武器
The tactical smooch is just one weapon in my vast arsenal.
再用一次  敌人可能就要动用核武器了
Well, employ it again, and the enemy might go nuclear.
好吧  总之这叠纸里能找到我之前行踪的线索
Okay, but somewhere in this pile is the answer to where I was.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
卡塞尔  我知道这对我们有多重要
Look, castle, I know how important this is to us,
但你得知道  这事希望不大
But you have to realize, this is a long shot,
如果没有奏效  我不希望你太失望
And I don't want you to be disappointed if it doesn't pan out.
有玩具
Toys.
沃利从无到有创建了这里
Wally built this place from the ground up.
真不敢相信他不在了
Seems impossible that he's gone.
斯托勒小姐  公司一切还好吗
Miss Stoller, was everything okay here at work?
他跟同事或对手起过冲突吗
Did he have any conflicts with colleagues or business rivals?
至少我没听说
Not that I'm aware of.
作为公司的副总裁
And as VP of the company,
要是有事我肯定会知道
I'm sure I'd know.
我知道他过去几周承受了不少压力
I understand that he was under pressure the past couple of weeks,
总是很晚回家
that he was coming home late.
-谁告诉你的  -他太太
- Who told you that? - His wife.
不好意思  但这不是真的
I'm sorry, but that's not true.
我是说  他也许的确有压力
I mean, he may have been under pressure,
但肯定不是因为工作
But it certainly wasn't here at work.
这么说  他并没有加班到很晚
So, he wasn't staying late?
没有  正相反
No, just the opposite.
他每周都有几天会早退
He was leaving early several days a week.
我没想到这个真能弹
I did not realize this would be on.
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道他为什么要早退吗
Do you know why he was leaving early?
不知道  他说他有些私事要处理
No, he said he was taking care of some personal things.
好像挺私密的  所以我没多问
It sounded private, so I didn't ask.
不过他可能告诉过他的助理
But maybe he told his assistant.
马特
Matt?
威利格先生跟你提过
Did Mr. Williger ever mention to you
-他为什么要早退吗  -没有
- why he was leaving early? - No.
其实他对这整件事都挺保密的
He was actually pretty secretive about the whole thing.
这东西居然就上了膛摆在这儿
You leave these loaded?
我问过被害人的妻子了
So, I checked with the vic's wife.
威利格先生声称在加班的那几天
The days that Mr. Williger claimed he was working late
正是他在公司早退的日子
are the exact same days he was leaving work early.
那就是至少有十多天
That leaves about 10 to 12 hours
他每天有10-12小时下落不明
over at least a dozen days that he's unaccounted for.
他干什么去了
What was he doing?
我刚查了他的电话和财务记录
I just went back through his phones and financials,
没有问题
And they are clean.
说实话  是太过干净了
In fact, they're too clean.
那些天从他离开公司
From the time he left work on those days
到他回家  期间完全没有任何记录
till the time he got home, there's no activity at all.
没有电话  也没有任何消费
No calls or purchases of any kind,
连地铁和出租车都没坐过
Not even subway or cab charges.
那么  不管他在干什么
So, whatever he was doing,
他不希望任何人知道  为什么
He wanted to keep it a secret from everyone. Why?
我们现在正需要卡塞尔的疯狂理论
What we could use right now is a crazy Castle theory.
话说回来  卡塞尔哪去了
Where is Castle, anyway?
他需要休息  我让他回家查他的线索去了
He needed a time out, so I sent him home to check his leads.
嗨  帅哥  嗨  帅哥
Hey, sexy. Hey, sexy.
肯定是蕾妮改了我的铃声
Lanie must have changed my ringtone.
-宝贝  有事吗  -有件奇怪的事
- Hola, preciosa. What's up? - Something weird.
你知道被害人脸上和手上的斑点吧
You know that discoloration on the victim's hands and face?
是工业清洁剂造成的
It was caused by an industrial cleaner.
看来有人用这个清洗了他的皮肤
It looks like someone scrubbed his skin with it
但是发生在他死后
but after he was already dead.
蕾妮  如果凶手是想销毁证据
Wait, Lanie, if the killer is trying to get rid of evidence,
为什么只洗手和脸的部分
why would he only scrub the hands and face?
不知道  但清洁剂不含漂白剂
Don't know, but the cleaner wasn't bleach-based,
所以我还是有可能从指缝提取到DNA
so I still may be able to pull DNA from under the fingernails.
我还在他衣服口袋发现了一张收据
I also found a receipt in the victim's pocket.
是布鲁克林区的一家咖啡店的
It's from a coffee shop in Brooklyn,
日期正是他失踪的那天
dated the day he disappeared.
威利格住曼哈顿  办公室在市中心
Williger lived in Manhattan, and his office was in midtown.
他去布鲁克林干什么
What was he doing out in Brooklyn?
你们俩去查查那家咖啡店
Why don't you guys canvass the coffee shop
看看有没有人见过威利格
for anyone that saw Williger?
明天一早我就去办
I'll get a search warrant for
他的办公室和住所的搜查令
his office and house first thing in the morning.
好啦  凯特
Come on, Kate.
这是他两个月后的第一个案子
It's his first case back after two months.
你不能指望一切都马上恢复原状
You didn't expect everything to be back to normal right away.
不是的  雷恩  只是
No, Lane. It's just...
我希望我们能回到从前
It's just I-I want it to be us again,
但我们之间却横着一道阴影
and it's like there's this shadow between us.
我是选择了信任他
Look, I-I am choosing to trust him
不论证据看起来如何
in spite of all of the evidence.
我只是  我希望相信
I-I just -- I want to believe --
-但你不知道能不能做到  -是的
- But you don't know if you can. - Yeah.
而他  他在假装一切都很好
And he's -- he's acting like everything is fine.
我们俩都是  但事实并非如此
We both are, but it's -- it's not.
也许悬赏是个不错的主意
Maybe this reward he's offering is a good thing.
也许能找到真相
Maybe it'll lead to the truth.
不  我不想知道你穿的是什么
No, I don't want to know what you're wearing.
你到底知不知道理查德·卡塞尔的消息
Now, do you have any information about Richard Castle or not?
谢谢
Thanks.
针捞得怎么样了
So, how goes the haystack?
显然  你是对的
Uh, apparently you were right.
-都不靠谱吗  -也不全是
- Nutjobs? - No. Not all of them.
还有一些是期待著名作家
Some are lonely women hoping for a call
理查德·卡塞尔来电的孤独女人
from the famous author Richard Castle.
应该是我的约会对象
That will be my date.
-你在约会啊  -没错  他叫罗伯特
- Ooh. You have a date? - Uh-huh. Robert.
我们是在悲伤辅导小组认识的  就是你...
We met at the grief counseling group when you were presumed...
-你约悲伤辅导小组的人  -没错
- You -- you picked up a man at grief counseling? - Yes.
-如果你能进屋去就更好了  -为什么
- Now, I will thank you to go into the other room. - Why?
因为当时
Because at the moment,
我们交往的基础是失去亲人
our relationship is based on mutual loss,
要是他发现你活着回来了
and if he finds out that you have returned and are alive,
这会  毁了这份感情的
It will just -- it will ruin everything.
妈妈  你知道我今早还上电视了吧
Mother, you realize I was on television this morning.
幸运的是罗伯特很有修养
Luckily Robert is a cultured man.
他不看电视
He does not watch television.
而且他只读《华尔街日报》
The only newspaper he reads is the Wall Street Journal,
而且感谢上帝  那上面不会有你的报道
which, thankfully, did not carry news of your return.
所以  进屋去
So, go.
快快快
Go. Go. Go.
卡塞尔  我相信她的本意是好的
Castle, I'm sure she means well.
不是这个问题  只是
It's not that. It's just, uh...
我真的以为有人能帮上忙
I really thought someone out there could help.
我们会解决的  卡塞尔  我们一起
We'll figure this out, Castle. Together.
失陪
Excuse me.
喂
Hello?
卡塞尔先生  我知道你在寻找答案
Mr. Castle, I understand you're looking for answers.
你是谁  你怎么弄到这个电话的
Who is this? How did you get this number?
我知道一些消息
Because I know things,
包括发生在你身上的事
including what happened to you.
你准备好知道真相了吗
Are you ready to hear the truth?
我觉得这样不好  我应该和你一起去
I don't like this. I should go with you.
他说了让我一个人来
He said I had to come alone.
我知道  但是你都不知道对方是谁
Yeah, but you don't even know who he is.
听起来像个间谍
He sounded like a spy.
你觉得这会不会和你父亲有关
Do you think this has something to do with your father?
这不是他的风格
It doesn't seem like his style.
到时间了
It's time.
跟我走
Walk with me.
你是谁
Who are you?
你知道得越少越好
The less you know, the better.
可你知道我发生了什么  怎么知道的
But you know what happened to me. How?
因为我当时和你在一起
Because I was with you.
它们对你做了那些事  我估计你也记不着了
I don't expect you to remember, not after what they did.
我很幸运逃出来了
I was lucky I escaped.
从哪逃出来的
Escape from where?
船上
The ship.
我是在一艘船上
I was on a ship.
所以我才在海里被发现
Which is why I was found at sea.
谁的船
Whose ship?
是一艘勘探船
It's a survey vessel.
至少他们是这么说的
At least that's what they claimed.
但我看到船上有武器
But I saw weapons on board.
我很确定那是艘攻击舰
Pretty sure it was an attack ship.
-这么说是军方的  -一定是
- So it was military. - Must have been.
否则它们为什么要把它藏在
I mean, why else would they keep it
月球的背光面
on the dark side of the moon
不让我们的科学家看见
where our scientists can't see it?
什么
Excuse me?
他们现在看上去和我们一样了
You know, they look like us now.
这就是他们绑走你的原因  为了复制你的皮肤
That's why they took you. To copy your skin.
你刚才说的船是指  宇宙飞船
So, when you say ship, you mean... spaceship?
他们入侵的时候我们将无力反抗
We'll be defenseless when the invasion comes.
我们必须要找到一个警示世人的办法
We have to find a way to warn people.
你能做到
You can tell people.
-你上过电视  -我  我会告诉他们
- You were on TV. - I'll -- I'll warn them. I'll, uh...
再跟我说一遍你是怎么知道我电话的
Tell me again. How did you get my phone number?
-我在电话公司上班  -当然了
- I work for the phone company. - Of course you do.
怎么了
So, what happened?
我真心不想说
I really don't want to talk about it.
你能  消停会吗
Would you... knock it off?
-来帮我找找  -抱歉
- Come help me search. - Sorry.
我不知道我父母是怎么做到的
I don't know how my parents did it.
做什么
Did what?
养育我和我的姐姐们  赚钱养家
Raise me, all my sisters, put food on the table,
还能供我学钢琴
and still manage to give me piano lessons.
孩子的花销很大  加上珍妮又不上班
With Jenny not working and all the baby expenses,
我都快入不敷出了
I'm barely making ends meet.
可能有必要再找一份工作了
Probably gonna have to get a second job.
他们好像在给仓库招聘保安
Looks like they're hiring security guards down at their warehouse.
你穿上保安的衣服一定不错
A Rent-a-Cop uniform would look good on you.
死者的桌子里有什么见不得人的秘密吗
Find any dark secrets in our victim's desk?
没有  这人简直是个圣人
Nah. This guy's a saint.
给慈善机构捐钱  他的员工也喜欢他
He gives to charity, his employees love him.
在我看来
As far as I can tell,
他根本就没有什么肮脏  见不得...
there's no indication of any dirty, little secr...
这抽屉里有东西
There's something in this drawer.
什么
What?
钥匙  新的
The keys. Brand-new.
不是他家里或公司的
And they aren't to his work or house.
手机  不需要登记的
The phone -- pay as you go.
一个月前用现金买的
Purchased a month ago using cash.
上面有通话记录吗
Any calls on it?
一堆  都是在他失踪那段时间打的
A bunch, all made during that unaccounted time
而且都是打给同一个人的  娜塔莉·门多萨  28岁
and all made to the same number, a Natalie Mendoza, 28.
她跟威利格是什么关系
What's her relation to Williger?
-我们还在查她的背景  -我有个想法
- We're still running background. - I may have a guess.
沃利的妻子说他们的狗死了以后他的行为就变了
Wally's wife said that his behavior changed after their dog died.
我去跟兽医确认了一下
I checked with the vet.
原来  那事没有那么简单
Turns out, there's a whole lot more to that story.
沃利让兽医不要写进报告里
Now, Wally asked the vet to keep it out of the report
为的是不让他妻子伤心
so as not to upset his wife,
但那只狗不是正常地死了
but the dog didn't just die.
-她是被毒死的  -毒死的
- She was poisoned. - Poisoned?
是的  兽医想检测一下毒物是什么
Yes, the vet wanted to run a test to find out what the toxin was,
但出于某种原因  沃利坚决地拒绝了
but for some reason, Wally adamantly refused.
兽医说他好像很受触动
Vet said he seemed pretty shaken up about it.
现在一切都说得通了
Well, now it makes perfect sense.
一部秘密电话
A secret phone,
跟门多萨爱巢的钥匙  对妻子撒谎
keys to Mendoza's love nest, lying to his wife.
这就是现实版《致命诱惑》
This is "Fatal Attraction."
沃利有了外遇
Wally was having an affair,
当他准备结束这一切时
and when he tried to end it,
娜塔莉不顾一切想要留住他
Natalie went all Glenn Close on him,
毒死他的狗就是为了警告他
poisoning his poor dog to send a message.
这也解释了沃利翘班的原因
Would explain why wally started missing work --
为了和他的情妇待在一起
To spend time with his mistress.
可最后  这还不够
But in the end, wasn't enough.
门多萨小姐  纽约警察
Miss Mendoza, NYPD.
门多萨小姐
Miss Mendoza?
门没锁
Unlocked.
有人吗  门多萨小姐
Hello? Miss Mendoza?
有人吗
Hello?
有血
Blood.
看上去好像她被割喉了
It looks like her throat's been slit.
你是化妆师
You're a makeup artist?
大多数是给低成本恐怖片做特效
Mostly for low-budget horror.
我整个早上都在修整这副新妆容
I spent all morning testing out this new look
然后就睡了个午觉
and then went to take a nap.
我能说这幅新的妆容
Can I just say, the new look --
很像那么回事
Very effective.
门多萨小姐  你和沃利·威利格是什么关系
Miss Mendoza, what was your relationship with Wally Williger?
-谁  -沃利·威利格
- Who? - Wally Wlliger.
他是威利格玩具公司的总裁
He's the C.E.O. Of Williger Toys.
非常抱歉  我不认识他
I'm sorry. I don't know who that is.
娜塔莉  不要说谎
Natalie, please don't lie to us.
我们有证据证明上个月你们之间
We've got evidence of several dozens of phone calls
-有过好几次通话记录  -我没有说谎
- between the two of you over the past month. - I'm not lying.
你越是否认  你看上去越有嫌疑
The more you deny it, the guiltier you look.
有什么嫌疑啊
The guiltier I look for what?
听着  我跟你们说了  我不认识他
Look, I told you. I don't know him.
但是为什么他会给你打电话
But why... was he calling you?
等等  这就是沃利
Wait. That's Wally?
-那么你确实认识他  -是的
- So you do know him? - Yeah.
但他告诉我他叫做乔
But he told me his name was Joe.
乔·梅尔斯
Joe Meyers.
那你和乔之间到底是什么关系
And what exactly was your relationship with Joe?
他雇我教他怎么用舞台化妆油彩
He hired me to teach him to use theatrical makeup.
他为什么要用舞台化妆油彩
Why would he need to use theatrical makeup?
为了一个他在做的研究项目
Uh, for a research project he was doing.
他想让我教他
He wanted me to teach him
怎么改头换面
how to completely change his appearance.
为了什么呢
To what?
他说他在研究社会对衰老的反应
Um, he said he was studying society's reaction to aging
让我把他化成
and wanted my help to transform him
一个七十岁的老头
In -- into a 70-year-old man.
失踪  化妆  这些都说不通
Missing time, makeup? None of this makes any sense.
一个玩具公司的总裁
What's the C.E.O. Of a toy company
为什么要偷偷地变装成一个老头呢
doing secretly dressing up as an old man?
我不知道  但娜塔莉说她只是教沃利
I don't know, but Natalie said she only taught Wally
怎么把化妆油彩涂到他的手和脸上
how to apply the makeup to his hands and face.
这也是凶手刷掉的部位
The same parts of the body the killer scrubbed.
-他想除掉那些油彩  -对
- He was trying to remove the makeup. - Right.
所以杀害沃利的凶手
So Wally's murder
一定和他的隐秘身份有着某种联系
is connected to his secret identity somehow.
你们知道沃利口袋里的那张收据吗
You know that receipt that was in Wally's pocket,
布鲁克林咖啡馆的
the one from the Brooklyn coffeehouse?
排查过了吗
Did teams canvass it?
今天早上  但是没有线索
This morning, but they got no hits.
你知道吗  让他们再去查一次
You know what? Have them canvass it again.
我们可能找错人了
We may have been looking for the wrong man.
阿丽克西斯  你来这做什么
Alexis. What are you doing here?
爸爸  这是麦克和劳伦亚·当斯
Dad, this is Mike and Lauren Adams.
他们有些东西你必须看一下
They have something you need to see.
六周前  我们在度蜜月
About six weeks ago, we were on our honeymoon.
我们几天前才开始整理照片
We just started going through the photos the last couple of days.
每去一个地方麦克都会为我拍照
Mike took pictures of me everywhere we went.
昨晚  我们发现了这个
Last night, we noticed this.
这里  在背景里
Here, uh, in the background.
卡塞尔先生  我觉得这是你
Mr. Castle, I think that's you.
这是我
That is me.
我在和谁说话
Who am I talking to?
卡塞尔  就是这个人
Castle, that's the guy
是马萨诸塞州海岸边房车里的那个人
from the trailer on the Massachusetts coast,
就是他骗我们见过你  之后就消失了
The one that lied about you and then disappeared.
这是在哪里拍的
Where was this photo taken?
蒙特利尔
Montreal.
奇怪  我在蒙特利尔做什么
What the hell was I doing in Montreal?
根据图片文件地理位置标签
So, according to the JPEG's geotag,
这张照片是在这里拍的
the photo was taken here,
你刚从这座建筑里走出
and this is the building you were coming out of.
蒙特利尔国际银行
Montreal Global Bank.
我去银行干什么呢
What was I doing at a bank?
爸  那把钥匙
Dad, the key!
那把缝进你的裤子
The one sewn into your pants...
在你被找到时发现的
...when they found you.
说不定...
What if...
这把钥匙是从银行搞到的
the bank is where it came from?
-保险箱的  -大小正合适
- A safe deposit box. - It's the right size.
我们得赶去那里
We need to get up there.
这是我们盼望好久的突破性进展
This is the break we've been waiting for.
好吧  我们这周末就去
Okay, fine. We'll go this weekend.
等不到周末  我们现在就得走
We can't wait for the weekend. We got to go now.
-我正办案呢  -没事  我自己去
- I'm in the middle of a case. - Fine. I'll go.
飞到蒙特利尔很快的
Montreal's a short flight.
我往返用不了几个小时
I'll be there and back a couple of hours.
不行  出了这么多岔子
No! Not after everything we've been through.
你绝不能自己一个人去
You're not going alone.
她说得对  你不能自己过去
She's right, dad. You can't go by yourself.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
对头
Yes.
她和我一起去
Yes. She'll go with me.
我们不知道那边什么情况
We have no idea what's out there,
也不知道什么人会在那里
no idea who's out there.
太冒险了
That's too risky.
那可是加拿大  能有多危险
It's Canada. How risky could it be?
而且我得提醒你  我是成年人
And need I remind you, I'm a grown man.
我不需要征求你的同意
I don't need to ask your permission.
我就是那么一说
That being said,
求你  求求你  我能去吗
please, please, can I -- can I -- can I go?
好吧
Okay, fine.
但答应你
But only because I know
完全是因为我知道她在你身边你不会犯傻
you're not gonna do anything stupid if she's with you.
-别让他做任何蠢事  -我保证
- Don't let him do anything stupid. - Promise.
拿你护照去  我来买机票
Grab your passport. I'll get the tickets.
警员用老头样子的照片
Hey, so uniforms re-canvassed at that coffee shop
重新排查了那家咖啡店
using the geezer photo.
有线索了
They got a hit.
一位顾客认出老沃利是附近的一名租客
A patron identified old-man Wally as a tenant at a nearby building.
好的  我马上到
Okay. I'll be right there.
现在我们知道沃利的钥匙是哪里的了
Now we know what Wally's keys were to.
他租了多久了
How long has he had this place?
管理员说他是三周之前开始租的
Super said he rented it three weeks ago.
现金支付的
Paid cash.
他是扮成老头的样子租的
At least the old-man version of him did.
这明显是他用来乔装打扮的地方
Yeah, this is obviously where he came to change.
不过是为了什么呢
Yeah. But to do what?
让鉴证科搜查一下房间
Have CSU sweep the room.
和周围邻居谈谈
Let's talk to neighbors,
说不定他们看到了什么
see if they saw anything.
就是这  照片里那栋建筑
That's it -- the building in the photo.
看起来眼熟吗
Any of it look familiar?
一点也不
No.
你真觉得答案就在里面吗
You really think the answer's inside?
只有一个办法才能知道
Only one way to find out.
爸  你要去哪里
Dad, where are you going?
打开38号箱子
Open box number 38.
你不能就这样走进保险箱室
You can't just walk into a safe deposit room.
你需要账号  签名卡
You need account info, signature cards.
我们都不确定这把钥匙就是这里的
We don't even know if that key came from here.
我自有办法
I have a plan.
爸
Dad.
你好  能不能帮我一个忙
Hi, there. I wonder if you can help me.
我想租一个保险箱
I'd like to rent a safe deposit box.
邻居不记得有任何访客
So, the neighbor doesn't remember any visitors
也从没有见过年轻的沃利
and she never saw young Wally,
但是老沃利给她钱让她帮忙遛狗和喂养
but old Wally was paying her to walk and feed the dog.
另一栋公寓  另一条狗  穿成这样
Another apartment, another dog, dressing up like this.
这家伙到底想干什么
What was this guy doing?
我不知道
I don't know,
不论是什么  他因此被害
but whatever it was, it got him killed.
你把它带到兽医那里看看
Why don't you take him to the vet?
也许它身上有那种芯片
Maybe he's got a microchip
可以告诉我们它是哪来的
that will tell us where he came from.
-这就去  -贝克特
- Right on. - Hey, beckett.
看来老头子喜欢中餐
Looks like our old man was fond of chinese food.
这个餐馆离这六站地铁
This is from a restaurant half a dozen subway stops away.
叫外卖可有点远啊
That's a long way to go for takeout.
是啊  我打电话过去
Yeah, so I called over there.
发现过去几周老沃利常去那吃饭
Turns out old-man Wally was a regular the last several weeks,
每天晚上都逗留到很晚  一直付现金
stopping by late every other night, always paying cash.
不管他去哪  一定在餐馆附近
So, wherever he was going, it was near that restaurant.
给您  卡塞尔先生
Here you go, Mr. Castle.
-115号盒子  -谢谢
- Box 115. - Thank you.
我能问个问题吗
And may I ask you something?
你觉得我脸熟吗
Do I look familiar to you?
不  不熟  我们见过面吗
Uh, no, I don't believe so. Have we met?
应该没有  我搞错
I guess not. My mistake.
能不能今天就打开这盒子呢
Is it possible to access this box today?
当然可以
Of course.
乔治  请你带着卡塞尔先生
George, would please take Mr. Castle
到保险库去
back to the safe deposit vault?
请跟我来  先生
Follow me, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
-哪个盒子  先生  -38号
- Which box, sir? - 38.
如果钥匙不匹配  我们会被抓起来的
If it's not the right key, we'll get caught.
先生
Sir?
好咧
Here we are.
-有什么问题吗  -没问题
- Is there a problem? - No. No problem.
钥匙有点卡住了
Just a little sticky.
你确定是这个盒子吗
Are you sure you have the right box?
是的  我肯定
Yep. Positive.
我去跟经理确认一下
I'll just check with the manager.
等等  我们再试一次
Wait, wait. Let's try one more time.
有点
A little...
打开了
There we go.
就是钥匙有点卡
It was just a little sticky.
-你觉得里面是什么  -我不知道
- What do you think's inside? - I don't know.
但有人千方百计也要我带着这把钥匙
But someone went to a lot of trouble to make sure I had a key.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
爸爸  是你的笔迹
Dad, that's your handwriting.
是啊  我不记得我写过这些了
Yeah, I don't remember writing those.
这些信是写给贝克特  奶奶  我
They're letters addressed to Beckett, gram, and me.
内存卡
A memory card?
到了  就是这家餐馆
All right. Here's the restaurant.
我去盘查  看这附近有没有人知道
I'll start a canvass, see if anyone else around here knows
被害人来这做什么
what the hell our victim was doing in the area.
不必了
Don't bother.
我想我知道他打哪来了
I think I know where he was coming from.
你好  需要我帮忙吗
Excuse me. Can I help you?
是的  我是贝克特探长  这位是莱恩警探
Yes. I'm Detective Beckett. This is detective ryan.
-你认得这个人吗  -认识  他是乔
- Do you recognize this man? - Yeah. That's Joe.
-你是怎么认识他的  -他是这的门卫
- Exactly how do you know him? - He's a janitor here.
两周前我雇他做兼职
I hired him part time two weeks ago.
-迈克  -什么事
- Hey, Mac. - Yeah?
稍等一会儿
Excuse me one second.
莱恩
Ryan.
这就是他乔装的原因
That's why he made himself up.
他不希望被他的员工认出
He didn't want his employees to recognize him.
什么样的总裁
What's a C.E.O. Of a company
会在自己公司做门卫呢
doing working as a janitor in his own warehouse?
他是卧底老板
It's undercover boss.
但是他做卧底是为了什么
But what was he going undercover for?
他是个很安静的人  独来独往
He was a quiet guy. He kept to himself mostly.
我从没想到他是总裁
I never would have guessed he was the C.E.O.
-上周五他在这上班吗  -是的
- Was he working here last Friday? - Yeah.
他4点开始值班
In fact, he came in for his shift at 4:00.
11点离开
He left at 11:00.
到周一的时候  他就没来上班了
And then on Monday, he didn't show.
那天有什么不寻常的事情发生吗
Did anything unusual happen that day?
-我想没有  -威利格先生来做卧底
- I don't think so. - Well, were there any problems here,
-是不是因为这里出了什么问题  -没有
- any reason that Mr. Williger would want to go undercover? - No.
上个月他和他的团队
He and his team came in
来过这做季度视察
last month for their quarterly inspection,
我们得到了令人欣喜的报告
and we got a glowing report.
那他在做门卫的这段期间呢
Well, how about when he was here as a janitor?
他做了或说了什么不寻常的事情吗
Did he do or say anything out of the ordinary?
上周发生了一件事
There was that thing last week.
什么事
Ah. What thing?
有个保安抓到他下班后在后勤办公室里
One of the guards caught him in the back office after hours
翻阅文件
riffling through some paperwork.
什么文件
What kind of paperwork?
主要是货单
Manifests mostly,
我们工厂的跟踪物流
tracking shipments from our factories.
保安警告了他
The guard admonished him.
他道歉了  大家就当这事算了
He apologized. Everybody moved on.
我们要看一下这些货单
Well, we need to see those manifests.
我问了他妻子  同事
I talked to his wife, his colleagues.
知不知道沃利在仓库做什么
If any of them know what Wally was doing around his warehouse,
他们都说不知情
they're not admitting to it.
你呢  有什么发现
How about you? What'd you find?
除了我们国家
Aside from our country outsourcing
把制造环节都外包给了亚洲
all its manufacturing needs to Asia,
一切都很正常
everything seems to be in order.
慢点  慢点
Slow down, slow down.
-进展如何  -三振出局了
- How'd it go? - Struck out.
流浪狗没有装微型芯片
Rover here didn't have a microchip,
所以没法知道它是哪来的
so we still don't know where he came from,
但兽医说他非常健康
but the vet said he's in perfect health.
我不明白的是  他为什么还有条狗
You know what I don't get? Why did he have a dog?
这是他卧底身份的一部分
I mean, was it part of his cover,
还是跟他那条死去的狗有关
or did it have something to do with his own dog's death?
我们遗漏了一些细节
We're missing something,
补上那些  一切就说得通了
something that makes all of this make sense.
莱恩  查一下沃利失踪当晚
Ryan, can you look into security and street-camera footage
仓库周围的监控录像
around Wally's warehouse the night that he disappeared?
我要知道他去哪了
I want to find out where he went.
好的  走  狗狗
Right. Come on, boy.
凯特
Kate.
卡塞尔
Castle?
记忆卡
A memory card.
三张记忆卡放在三个信封里
Yeah, there were three of them in three separate envelopes --
一个给阿丽克西斯  一个给我妈  另一个给你
one for Alexis, one for my mother, and one for you.
里面有什么
What's on it?
看吧
Watch.
凯特  如果你正在看
Kate, if you're seeing this...
如果看到这段片子  我可能已经死了
Well, if you're seeing this, I'm probably dead.
我想让你知道  我从没打算要离开你
I-I want you to know, I never intended to leave you,
不会像这样  不会在我们结婚当天
not like this, not on our wedding day,
但我身不由己
but I-it wasn't my choice.
我希望我能告诉你这是怎么回事
I wish I could tell you what's going on.
我...希望我能解释
I...wish I could explain.
你只需知道  我爱你
But just know that I love you.
永远爱你
I've always loved you.
永远
Always.
给阿丽克西斯和我妈的也差不多是这样
The ones to Alexis and my mother were pretty much the same.
凯特  我做了什么啊
Kate, what did I do?
我不知道
Mm. I don't know.
不知道
I don't.
或许我们有办法查出来
But maybe there's a way we can find out.
文件里没有元数据
There's no metadata on the file,
也没有地理标签
and it wasn't geotagged.
能不能查出它是在哪拍的
Is there any other way to find out where this was taken?
或许房间里有什么线索
Maybe there's something in the room
或者在音频里
or something in the audio.
录像是低画质的  没什么线索
The recording's low quality, so there's not much to go on,
但我会再挖掘一下
but I'll see what I can dig up.
真奇怪
It's weird.
我看到这个之前
Before I saw that,
只想知道我去了哪里  做了什么
all I wanted to know was where I was and what I was doing.
现在我不确定了
Now I am not so sure.
卧底老板有什么新进展了吗
Any news on your undercover boss?
所有的发现都导出了新的疑问
Every answer just leads to more questions.
我不知道他在仓库做了什么
I have no idea what he was doing at that warehouse
他跟狗在一起干什么
or what this guy was doing with him.
其实我很希望
Actually, I was kind of hoping that you might be able
你的疯狂理论能帮忙
to help me with a crazy theory.
抱歉  我黔驴技穷  亲一个怎么样
Sorry. I'm fresh out. How about a kiss?
更好
Even better.
他前世是个修女吧[大叔故意性别错乱]
You think he was a nun in a previous life?
警官  你口袋里有什么
Detective, what do you have in your pocket?
物证  搜查时找到的
Evidence...from a bust.
这女孩在贩毒
The girl was dealing.
他不是条普通的狗  是训练有素的缉毒犬
So he's not just a dog. He's a trained drug dog.
我想我又有疯狂理论了
I think I have a crazy theory for you.
你认为沃利在做的事是这个吗
That's what you think Wally was up to?
那是我听过的最疯狂的推论
Well, that is the craziest story I've ever heard.
我承认很疯狂
I admit it's crazy,
但这是唯一与所有事实相符的推论
But it's the only story that matches all the facts.
卡塞尔说得对
Castle's right.
就算对  也只是推论
Even if he is, it's still just a story.
我们没有证据
We don't have any proof.
我想我知道该如何找证据了
I think I know how we can find some.
卡塞尔  你和我一起去吗
Castle, you coming with me?
你不介意的话  我想在这里待会儿
Uh, if you don't mind, I'd like to stay here for a while.
好的  我马上回来
Okay. I'll be back soon.
走吧  伙计们
Come on, guys.
有线索吗
Any luck?
你在城市里  我只知道这么多
I know this much. You were in a city.
-你怎么知道的  -窗户外
- How can you tell? - Out the window.
-完全一片白  -不是完全
- It's completely white. - Not completely.
摩天大楼
Skyscrapers.
-你知道这是哪里吗  -不知道
- So, do you know where this is? - No.
但窗外的景色
But this view out the window,
大厦的外形应该是独一无二的
the configuration of buildings ought to be unique.
这样说你可以找到
So you can find it?
理论上是  但将此数据
Theoretically, but comparing this data set
与全球3D地图作比较  所需时间太长
to global 3D mapping would take forever
我的计算机也没这个运算能力
and more computing power than I have.
如果范围缩小到一座城市呢
What if we narrowed it to just one city?
蒙特利尔  你可以找到吗
Montreal? Could you do it then?
不知道  只能试试
I don't know. Best I can do is try.
无法想象收到自己这样的消息
Can't imagine how freaky it must be getting a message
却不记得录制的经过  该有多诡异
like that from myself and not remember recording it.
他是如何应对这些的
How's he doing with it all?
他需要答案  我们都需要
He needs answers. We both do.
你觉得需要多长时间
How long do you think this is gonna take?
我怎么知道  我甚至不确定有没有用
Hell if I know. I'm not even sure it's going to work.
我是艾利斯
This is Ellis.
马上来
I'm on it.
我们来看看卡塞尔的推论是否正确
All right, let's see if Castle is right.
慢点  小子  慢点
Easy, boy. Easy!
它发狂了
He's really going crazy.
别这样  小子
Come on, boy.
不
No!
别这样
Come on!
喂  怎么回事
Hey. What the hell's going on here?
这些箱子从哪里来的
Where did these boxes come from?
我们在中国的制造商
Our manufacturer in China.
看里面
Check inside.
毒品
Drugs.
谁负责这批货的
Who's in charge of this shipment?
麦克沃伊
Mcavoy!
放开我  我发誓  我没有杀他
Let me go! I swear I didn't kill him!
是吗  那是谁杀的
Yeah? Then who did?
对不起  斯托勒小姐  他们坚持要进来
I'm sorry, miss Stoller. They insisted.
没事  马特
That's fine, Matt.
我们在和威利格夫人过公司的账
We were just going over the company's finances with Mrs. Williger.
调查有进展吗
Has there been any progress in the investigation?
是的  有
Yes, there has.
我们知道了你丈夫被杀的原因
We know why your husband was killed,
是从你家的狗被杀开始的
And it started with your dog.
我的狗  安妮
My dog? Annie?
一个月前  你的丈夫
Yeah, a month ago, your husband
去了公司在布鲁克林的仓库
went to the company warehouse in Brooklyn.
我们相信他在那里的时候
We believe that while he was there,
他捡了一个阳光莎拉娃娃
he picked up a sunshine Sarah doll
给安妮做咬咬玩具
to use as a chew toy for Annie.
-是  它喜欢这些娃娃  -只是这一个令它没命
- Yes, she loved those dolls. - Except this one killed her.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
娃娃里有毒品
There were drugs inside of it.
这不可能
That's impossible.
沃利也是这样想的
That's most likely what Wally thought
所以他开始乔装
and why he started wearing disguises,
早下班  晚回家
leaving early, and coming home late.
他日复一日地去仓库
He went back to the warehouse day after day
想弄清楚是怎么回事
trying to figure out what had happened
直到他快查到真相时被他们杀害了
until he got too close and they had him killed.
-谁杀了他  -你仓库里的贩毒集团
- Who had him killed? - The drug ring running out of your warehouse.
他们把海洛因藏在那些娃娃里
They were smuggling heroin into the country from China
然后从中国走私过来
inside of those dolls.
斯托勒小姐  我们问过你的工头
Miss Stoller, we talked to your foreman.
他告诉我们夜班人员会先从娃娃中
He told us how the night shift would remove the drugs
取出毒品  再把它们归入库存
from the dolls before returning them to the inventory.
我们库房的员工绝对不可能做这种事的
There's no way our warehouse employees could pull that off.
所有那些货都是从这里调配的
All of those shipments are coordinated from here.
没错  就在这间办公室里
Yes. From this office.
也就是说负责走私毒品的人
Which means whoever was in charge of it
肯定能拿到威利格先生的文件
had to have had access to Mr. Williger's files.
你这是去哪啊  兄弟
Where you going, bro?
我只是
Oh, I'm just --
你跑不了的
You'll never make it.
-马特  -马特·门罗
- Matt? - Matt Monroe.
他进公司前  一直住在亚洲
Before he joined the company, he was living over in Asia.
实际上  这正是威利格雇你的原因
In fact, that's one of the reasons Williger hired you,
因为你熟悉当地文化
your familiarity with local cultures.
我想威利格先生没想到
I guess Mr. Williger wasn't aware
对亚洲文化的精通还包括海洛因交易
that familiarity extended to their heroin trade.
工头说你是这一切的幕后主使
The foreman said you were behind the whole operation.
-他撒谎  -是吗  他说他打过电话给你
- He's lying. - Really? 'Cause he said that he called you,
说他怀疑那个到处打探的
told you he was suspicious
新来的门卫
about the new janitor who had been poking around
你说你会处理的
you said you'd take care of it?
那正是威利格先生消失的那晚
That was the same night that Mr. Williger disappeared.
发现那个老头居然是你老板
Must have been quite a surprise
你肯定吓了一跳吧
when you realized the old man was your boss.
我跟这件事一点关系也没有
I had nothing to do with this.
我们再次核查了街上的监控录像
We double-checked street cams.
这是沃利刚下班的时候  而你的车
This is your car three blocks from the warehouse
就停在离仓库三个街区外的地方
just after Wally ended his shift.
而且我敢打赌我们提取的DNA样本
And I bet the DNA samples that we collect
也会证实我们所说的一切
are gonna confirm what we already know.
马特·门罗  你因谋杀
Matt Monroe, you're under
沃利·威利格而被捕
arrest for the murder of Wally Williger.
警探  如果沃利察觉到不妥
Detective, if Wally knew something was wrong,
他为什么要隐瞒所有人呢
why did he hide it from everyone?
他不知道可以信任谁
He didn't know who he could trust,
而他也不能去找有关部门  因为
and he couldn't go to the authorities because --
因为那样的话  我们公司
Because our company name
就跟贩毒划上了等号
would become synonymous with drug smuggling.
我是托瑞  卡塞尔跟你在一起吗
Hey, it's Tory. Is Castle with you?
没啊  怎么了
No. Why?
我认为他可能去了蒙特利尔
I think he might be in Montreal.
你不该回来的
You weren't supposed to come back.
永远不该
Ever.
是你
It's you.
你记得什么
What do you remember?
什么都不记得
Nothing.
很好
That's good.
我知道你参与了此事
I know you're involved.
我也知道你清楚我身上发生了什么
I know you know what happened to me.
你是谁
Who are you?
你不能这么做
You can't be doing this,
到处问问题  还悬赏
asking questions, offering rewards.
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
那就告诉我到底发生了什么
Then tell me what happened.
你没听明白  卡塞尔先生  你必须停手
You're not listening, Mr. Castle. You need to stop.
不然呢
Or what?
不然你将会发现真相
Or you're going to find out the truth.
而你说过你不想记得
And you said you didn't want to remember.
我们竭尽全力确保你不记得
We went to great lengths to make sure that you didn't.
但如果你继续找下去的话
But if you keep looking...
我绝不可能主动要求失忆
There's no way in hell I asked for this.
对不起
I'm sorry.
但这真是你要求的
But you did.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
霍兰德森林  卡塞尔先生
Hollander's Woods, Mr. Castle.
你11岁那年二月里的一天
That February day when you were 11 years old.
不
No.
那天发生的事
What happened to you there,
才是你成为罪案作家的真正原因
the real reason you became a mystery writer.
你怎么会
How did you...
我从来没跟任何人说过那件事
I never told anyone about that.
不
No.
贝克特不知道  你家人也不知道
Not Beckett, not your family.
但你告诉了我
But you told me,
三周前
three weeks ago
以便遇到现在这种情况  你有证据
so that if this ever happened, you'd have proof.
你会知道是你要求被抹去记忆
You'd know that you were the one who asked to forget.
我要求的
I asked for this?
有些谜题本就不该被解开
Some mysteries aren't meant to be solved.
都结束了
It's over now.
回家
Go home.
好好生活  忘了这一切发生过
Live your life. Forget this ever happened.
这是你的意愿
It's what you wanted.
你怎么能孤身前去  不告诉我们
How could you go up there on your own and not even tell us?
因为我知道你会阻止我
Because I knew you would try and stop me,
我想知道真相  但...
and I needed to know, but...
但现在
But now...
我会做了什么穷凶极恶之事
what could I have done that was so bad
以致于我让他们抹去我的记忆呢
that I asked them to make me forget?
也许你什么也没做
Maybe you didn't do anything.
也许你发现了什么糟糕的事情
Maybe you found out something terrible
或是目睹了什么你不想一辈子记着的事情
or witnessed something you didn't want to have to live with.
或许过去的两个月就像是潘多拉盒子
Or maybe the past two months is like pandora's box
不该被打开
and shouldn't be opened.
我对他们和你的所作所为
What I did to them, to you...
我怎么能就这么忘却
how am I supposed to just let that go?
我不知道
I don't know.
我妈妈的谋杀案我也想忘却来着
I tried with my mom's murder.
遇到你之前  一直被我埋在心底
I buried it until you came along.
你认为有可能吗
You think it's possible?
在不知真相的情况下生活下去
To live with it without ever knowing?
卡塞尔
Oh, Castle...
不是一码事
This is completely different.
你身上不管发生了什么事  你已经知道了真相
Whatever happened to you, you already knew the truth,
你决定你不想记得这件事
and you decided that you didn't want to remember it anymore.
尽管我们都很想知道事情的原委
And as much as we wanted to know the answers,
但如果你做了决定  一定事出有因
if you decided that, then there had to have been a reason.
也许这就是我要他们抹去我记忆的原因
Maybe that's why I asked them to make me forget.
以便我能回到你身边
So I could come home to you.
你知道吗
You know what?
什么
What?
我们应该结婚
We should get married.
明早就结
Tomorrow, first thing.
忘掉这一切  你看如何
Put all this behind us. What do you say?
卡塞尔
Castle...
我很想嫁给你
...there is nothing that I want more than to marry you,
但这样不行
but not like this.
你还没准备好
You're not ready?
不  我们都没准备好
No. We're both not ready.
我们在寻找一块结实的地面
We're looking for solid ground,
你以为结了婚就能让你释怀
and you think getting married is gonna fix the way you feel,
不会的
and it won't.
我爱你
Look, I love you.
我会站在你身边
And I'm here for you.
但我们需要一些空间
But we need to get some distance from all of this.
回到原来的生活
We need to get back to our own lives,
一起找到结实的地面
find solid ground together.
我向你保证  我哪都不会去
I promise you, I'm not going anywhere.
等了这么久  我希望一切十全十美
We've waited this long, so let's just make it right.
多久
How long?
一个月
A month.
没有期待  没有压力
No expectations, no pressure.
就你和我
Just us.
然后我们再谈结婚
And then we'll talk about it then.
一个月
A month.
就这么定了
It's a date.